Guide to the Jeff Yang Collection on A Magazine TAM.858
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Jeff Yang Collection on A. Magazine
1974-2024
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Yang, Jeff
TAM.858
4.17 Linear Feet in 6 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize flat box, and 4 folders in shared housing
4.81 Gigabytes in 1 recording
A. Magazine: Inside Asian America was an East-Coast-based magazine that reported on issues geared towards a young, Asian American audience. During the height of circulation, A. Magazine was the largest magazine dedicated to Asian American pop-culture, politics, traditions, and achievements. Through 1998-1999 A. Magazine sales and profitability reached a market-competitive level with an increase in circulation and advertising. At the height of publication, A. Magazine reached a circulation high of 200,000, becoming the best selling Asian American serial in the country. The Jeff Yang Collection on A. Magazine (dated 1974-2024) consists of materials created and collected by Yang documenting A. Magazine's creation, publication, management, and impact, as well as other projects from Metro East Publications/aMedia. Materials include press coverage, business records, event programs, issues of A. Magazine, and issues of Chinese language newspapers and magazines. The collection also includes administrative records and correspondence regarding Metro East Publications and aMedia, including litigation, financial records, accounting reports, and business summaries, as well as meeting notes and correspondence regarding the Board of Directors and shareholders. Also included is a electronic recording of an interview of Yang conducted by the Asian/Pacific/American Institute at New York University, in which Yang discusses his life and the creation of A. Magazine.
Scope and Contents
The Jeff Yang Collection on A. Magazine (dated 1974-2024) consists of materials created and collected by Yang documenting A. Magazine's creation, publication, management, and impact, as well as other projects from Metro East Publications/aMedia. Materials include press coverage, business records, event programs, issues of A. Magazine, and issues of Chinese language newspapers and magazines. The collection also includes administrative records and correspondence regarding Metro East Publications and aMedia, including litigation, financial records, accounting reports, and business summaries, as well as meeting notes and correspondence regarding the Board of Directors and shareholders. Also included is a electronic recording of an interview of Yang conducted by the Asian/Pacific/American Institute at New York University, in which Yang discusses his life and the creation of A. Magazine.
Appraisal
The following items were appraised out the collection: a flash drive with a duplicate copy of an interview with Yang, a removable media card with commercial Asian comics, and floppy disks with a photograph and biography of Yang already in the physical collection.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Jeff Yang in September 2025; the accession number associated with this gift is 2025.083.
Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted. An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.
Biographical Note
Jeff Yang is a writer, journalist, and business consultant. He was a co-creator and publisher of A. Magazine, an East-Coast-based magazine geared towards a young, Asian American audience.
Historical Note
A. Magazine was an East-Coast-based magazine geared towards a young, Asian American audience. During the height of circulation, A. Magazine was the largest magazine dedicated to Asian American pop-culture, politics, traditions, and achievements in the United States. In 1989, Jeff Yang, William Yao, Sandra Kim, and Amy Chu met in Cambridge, Massachusetts to discuss the need for a national publication that would speak to, for, and about Asian Americans, and launched Metro East Publications (MEP). In 1990, MEP released the first official issue of A. Magazine, produced by a small team of volunteer staff led by Yang. At its initial launch, A. Magazine was a community-based publication with limited national circulation. There were no paid advertisements and all funding for the project was secured through community fundraising events. In 1993, the company relaunched A. Magazine as a commercial publication; they opened their first permanent office space in New York City and hired new full-time staff, including advertising salespersons and administrative assistants. Through 1998-1999 A. Magazine sales and profitability reached a market-competitive level with an increase in circulation and advertising. At the height of publication, A. Magazine reached a circulation high of 200,000, becoming the best selling Asian American serial in the country. After a name change to aMagazine and a new parent company in aMedia, the publication ceased in 2002.
Magazines (Periodicals); Journalism; Asian Americans and mass media; Asian Americans -- Ethnic identity.; Yang, Jeff
- Meeting Documents, 1994-1999 (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
- Shareholder Documents and Meetings, 1993-1999 (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
- A. Magazine Correspondence, 1994-2000 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
- Financial Statements and Accountants' Reports, 1994-1999 (Box 1, Folder 10, Box 2, Folder 1-3)
- Business Plans, Reports, and Documents, 1989-1998 (Box 2, Folder 4-8, Box 3, Folder 1-3)
- Press, 1974, 1993-2009 (Box 3, Folder 4-8, Box 4, Folder 1-8, Box Shared Tamiment 208, Folder 4-6, Box Shared Tamiment 203, Folder 5)
- Legal Documents, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 9-10, Box 5, Folder 1-3)
- Events, Awards, 1993-2001 (Box 5, Folder 4-9)
- Jeff Yang Bio, circa 1996 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- About A. Magazine, 1994, undated (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
- News Releases, 1998-1999 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Ephemera, Notes, Project Files, 1990-1998 (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
- Issues of A. Magazine, 1991-1993 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Issues of A. Magazine, 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Issues of A. Magazine, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 8-9)
- Issues of A. Magazine, 1998-1999 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Issues of A. Magazine, 1999-2000 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Issues of A. Magazine, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Issues of A. Magazine, 2000-2001 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Issues of A. Magazine, 2001-2002 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Interview with Jeff Yang, 2024 November 11; TW_TAM_858_ER_1